<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "dtd/dblite.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % Symbols SYSTEM "Symbols.ent">
%Symbols;
]>
<section id="SaveImageDialog">
	<?dbhh topicname="IDH_DIALOG_SAVE_IMAGE" topicid="80"?>
	<title>Save as image</title>
	<indexterm><primary>save</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>picture</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>image</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>metafile</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>bitmap</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary><filename>bmp</filename></primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary><filename>emf</filename></primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary><filename>png</filename></primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary><filename>gif</filename></primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary><filename>jpg</filename></primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		Use the menu item <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu><guimenuitem>Save as image...</guimenuitem></menuchoice> to save the shown coordinate system as an image file.
		Graph supports five formats: Windows Enhanced Metafile (emf), Windows Bitmap (bmp), Portable Network Graphics (png), Joint Photographic Experts Group (jpeg) and Portable Document Format (pdf).
		When the menu item has been chosen, a standard <guilabel>Save As</guilabel> dialog will appear.
		In this dialog you write a filename, choose a directory and select one of the image types.
	</para>
	<para>
		bmp and png are both bitmaps, and the picture will be saved exactly like you see it on the screen.
		emf files are used for vector graphics.
		The Options button in the save dialog can be used to change the image size.
		You may also be able to change other settings depending on the chosen image format.
	</para>
	<para>
		Metafiles (emf) should be the preferred format, because it is small and looks nice even then it is scaled.
		Windows Bitmap (bmp) is a standard format supported by almost all Windows programs that can read graphics files.
		Portable Network Graphics (png) is a format that is better compressed than bmp files.
		This is the most sustainable format for web pages, because it is small and can be understood by all browsers.
	</para>
	<para>
		Joint Photographic Experts Group (jpeg) is a bitmap format with loss.
		It is supported but not recommended because graphs will usually become blurred.
	</para>
	<para>
		Portable Document Format (pdf) is actually not an image format.
		It is a way to store documents as postscript in a portable way.
		Graph will store the image as Portable Network Graphics inside the pdf file.
	</para>
	<para>
		CompuServe Graphics Interchange (gif) is not supported because it uses the LZW compression, which is patented by Unisys.
	</para>
</section>
