<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "../dtd/dblite.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % Symbols SYSTEM "Symbols.ent">
%Symbols;
]>
<section id="TableDialog">
	<?dbhh topicname="IDH_DIALOG_TABLE" topicid="150"?>
	<title>Calc|Table</title>
	<indexterm><primary>calc</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>table</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>evaluate</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		The dialog shown below is used to evaluate the selected function for a range of x-coordinates.
		You specify the first and last x-coordinate in the range, and set the distance between the x-values in the interval.
		When you press the button labeled <guibutton>Calc</guibutton>,
		the table will be filled with the x-values in the interval and their corresponding values for f(x), f'(x) and f''(x).
		While the values are calculated, the program displays a progress indicator, which indicates how much of the calculations have been done.
	</para>

	<graphic fileref="DialogTable.png"/>

	<para>
		After the table has been filled you may look through them by scrolling with the panel to the right.
		You can select some cells with the mouse and right click with the mouse and choose <guimenuitem>Copy</guimenuitem> to copy the cells to the clipboard.
		From the clipboard the data may be pasted into other programs as Microsoft Excel.
	</para>

	<para>
		When you move the mouse to the left side of the table the cursor changes to a right pointing arrow.
		Now you can select whole rows with the mouse.
		When you move the mouse to the top of the table the cursor changes to a down pointing arrow.
		Now you can select whole columns with the mouse.
		The whole table may be selected by right clicking and selecting <guimenuitem>Select all</guimenuitem>.
		It is also possible to select cells by holding down the shift key and using the arrow keys on the keyboard.
	</para>

	<para>
		From the right click menu it is also possible to export the selected data to a file as comma or tab delimited text.
	</para>

	<para>
		Note that is you choose to create a lot of values in the table, it may take some time to calculate.
		Many values may also take up a lot of memory from the system.
	</para>
</section>
