<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter SYSTEM "../dtd/dblite.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % Symbols SYSTEM "Symbols.ent">
%Symbols;
]>
<section id="AnimateDialog">
	<?dbhh topicname="IDH_DIALOG_ANIMATE" topicid="160"?>
	<title>Calc|Animate</title>
	<indexterm><primary>animate</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>constant</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>avi</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>repeat</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>reverse</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>auto reverse</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>custom constant</primary></indexterm>
	<indexterm><primary>frames per second</primary></indexterm>
	<para>
		This dialog is used to create an animation by changing a custom constant.
		The animation can be played directly, saved to a file or copied into a document.
		The animation can contain all elements supported by Graph, for example functions, relations, point series, labels, etc.
	</para>

	<graphic fileref="DialogAnimate.png"/>

	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Constant</term>
			<listitem>
				Here you select which constant you want to change in the animation.
				The constant must already have been created in the <link linkend="CustomFunctionsDialog">Custom functions</link> dialog.
				The selected constant will be changed in each frame in the animation.
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>

		<varlistentry>
			<term>Range</term>
			<listitem>
				You need to specify the range of the selected constant in the animation.
				The <guilabel>Step</guilabel> value indicates how much the constant is changed between two frames.
				The number of frames is given by (<guilabel>To</guilabel> - <guilabel>From</guilabel>) / <guilabel>Step</guilabel>.
				More frames will give a smoother animation but it will also take longer to create and take up more space in the disk file.
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>

		<varlistentry>
			<term>Image information</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					You can specify the image size of the animation.
					This will affect the file size and the time it takes to create the animation.
					The <guilabel>Frames per second</guilabel> indicates the default speed of the animation.
					Most players will be able to adjust the speed when the animation is played.
				</para>
				<para>
					When you press the <guibutton>Animate</guibutton> button, an animation is created from the settings you have specified.
					This may take some time depending on what elements exist in the coordinate system and how many frames are needed.
				</para>
				<para>
					When the animation is finished, a very simple player is shown.
					You can use this to play the animation.
					The rightmost button will give you some additional options, for example to save the animation to a file, which can be played by any media player.
					You can also have the player repeat playing the animation until you stop it.
					The <guimenuitem>Auto reverse</guimenuitem> option will make the animation run backwards when it reaches the end.
					This is very useful in combination with the <guimenuitem>Repeat</guimenuitem> option to make the animation oscillate between the two ends.
					You can also make some changes to the speed, though a more accurate speed needs to be set before the animation is created.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>
